RAKESH RATHI

Website: www.rathirakesh.com
Email: rathirakesh7@gmail.com
Contact: +91 7904719733

SUMMARY

A software engineer with almost one year of experience, I live by the broad definition "Engineering is the method of exploiting and utilizing existing knowledge and resource to benefit mankind". I have always been driven by what potential impact my work produces and the value it can bring about, be it in whatever domain.

I work at WIPRO as part of the CITI Bank server automation team to drive automation across OS platforms like RHEL/AIX/Windows using configuration management and orchestration tools like Ansible and Chef.

EMPLOYMENT

WIPRO

Software Developer

April 2019 - Present

- Developed a pipeline for on-demand cookbook decommission using Ruby and Groovy scripts, which helps operation team in managing configuration across almost 125k cloud and non-cloud servers.
- Developed numerous Ansible playbooks for configuration management across all the servers.
- Developing highly scalable Rest API's in Spring and Golang, which are consumed by multiple Citi services.

HASURA

Software Developer Intern

Dec 2017 - Feb 2018

- Developed an android application from scratch which triggers a zap from webhook to google sheet and deployed it on Hasura Hub, which helps Hasura community people as a quick-start.
- Worked in a team of 4 interns and learnt about team collaboration and various stages involved in software development lifecycle.

EDUCATION

Bharath Institute of Higher Education and Research (Chennai)

CGPA 9.14/10.0 B-Tech in Computer Science and Engineering (2015-2019)

Shri Maheshwari Senior Secondary School (Rajasthan)

81% Matriculation RBSE (2013)

76% Intermediate RBSE (2015)

KEY PROJECT

Linux Shell

- Designed a Linux Shell in C language which does not contain any configuration file.
- During its lifecycle it **reads** the command from standard inputs, **parse** the command into program and arguments and then **executes** the command.

SKILLS

Languages and Frameworks: Java, C, JavaScript, Ruby, Groovy, Spring, Golang, React-Native, Native Base

Databases: Mongodb, MySQL

DevTools and Other Skills: Data Structure and Algorithm, Linux Shell, Eclipse, Git, Git Bash, ELK, CRW

AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Scored 80% in IMAD course conducted by NPTEL IIT Madras.
- Handled many sessions on C programming for CS/IT department students.
- Superior Performance Award from Hasura.